

PROFILE

Experienced Electrical Design Engineer, Sr. Sales Support Engineer, Project Engineer, Site Engineer, and Project Sr. Supervisor with a demonstrated history of working in the Electrical Sub-station Equipment Manufacturing Industry. Skilled in AutoCAD, DIALux, Electrical Distribution System Design, Industrial Electrical System Equipment Manufacturing, Lighting Design, Lightning Protection System (LPS) design and implementation, Industrial Building Services, Steel Structures Electrical Safety and Protection Assessments. Strong engineering professional with a B.Sc. Engineering focused in Electrical and Electronic Engineering graduated from University Of Asia Pacific.

CONTACT & ADDRESS

Cellphone: +8801671658026 Email: sarkerkader444@gmail.com

Address: Holding No-190, Sundalpur, Dashpara,

Daudkandi, Cumilla, Bangladesh.

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdul-

kadir-sarker-6b4991113/

MEMBERSHIP

- Member of Institution of Engineers,
 Bangladesh, from 2017 to till now.
- Volunteer at Volunteer for Bangladesh (VBD) in 2014.

CERTIFICATES FROM IEEE

- NESC 2017 (2017 National Electrical Safety Code),
- Local Infrastructure Service
 Delivery in Developing Countries
- Village Energy: Understanding Rural Energy Needs
- Sustainable Electrification Solution for Developing countries and
- (EGD) Engineering for Global Development

ABDUL KADIR SARKER

Electrical Engineer

(MEP Department)

Current Address: F: D2, H: 37, R: 10, South Baridhara R/A DIT Project, Badda, Dhaka-1212

WORK EXPERIENCE: 6+ YEARS

- Project Senior Supervisor- at Sanyo Engineering & Construction Inc. Bangladesh Branch (Suntec Group, Japan) – July 15, 2018 to till now
- Sr. Engineer, Technical & Sales Support- at Mampower Limited/SBEL (Superior Group, Bangladesh) – April 20, 2017 to June 30, 2018.
- III. Electrical Design Engineer- at Elements Bangladesh (MEP Consulting & Engineering Farm, Bangladesh) November 01, 2014 to April 19, 2017.

EDUCATION

- University of Asia Pacific
 2010 2014, Dhaka, Bangladesh
 B.Sc. in Electrical and Electronic Engineering
- Dhaka Bigyan College
 2006 2008, Dhaka, Bangladesh
 Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC), Science
- Sundalpur High School
 2004 2006, Dhaka, Bangladesh
 Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC), Science

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- ✓ AutoCAD 2D 3D, Isometric
- ✓ DIALux, BlindoCAD
- ✓ Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- ✓ SketchUp 2018
- ✓ SketchUp Free

PROFESSIONAL KEY SKILLS

- ✓ Design Drawings, Working Drawings, Shop Drawings, As-Built Drawings
- ✓ Association and coordination in Electrical Safety Audit and Energy Audit
- ✓ Method of Statement, Schedules, Inspection Reports, Activity Reports
- ✓ Site Management, Site Supervision, Cashbook Accounting of site expenses
- ✓ Supervision of Lifting works, Transportation works
- ✓ Construction Risk Assessment, Safety Measures, MEP Constructions etc.
- ✓ Weekly and Monthly Report of Progress

INTERNATIONAL TRAVEL

- ✓ Hanoi, Vietnam
- ✓ Agartala, India

WORK EXPERIENCE DETAILS

PROJECT SR. SUPERVISOR, AT SANYO ENGINEERING & CONSTRUCTION INC DURATION: JULY 2018 – PRESENT

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Currently working as Project Sr. Supervisor for Sanyo Engineering & Construction Inc. Bangladesh Branch at the project division for supporting several projects from Dhaka Office.
- Study and explain to Electrical and Mechanical Supervisors the Method of Statements for Installation of Electromechanical and Plumbing (MEP) System.
- Preparing the Work Schedule of MEP Works for the Site as per the civil works at site and report to Construction Manager.
- Overall Supervision of MEP installation works at project site and inspection of the quality of works of the worker and technician.
- Preparing Requisition form and submitting to Logistic Department of Branch Office and checking Quotation from Suppliers for materials for site.
- Preparing and Submitting to Construction Manager the Daily Activity Report and Daily Work Procedure.
- Preparing the Request for Inspection (RFI) and submitting to the Engineer/Consultant of the Roads and Highways of Government of Bangladesh.
- Making shop drawings for the site and working drawing for supervisors and being responsible for the project site works updates and reports to Project Manager.
- Preparing the checklist for QC inspection and coordinating with Engineer/consultant regarding Engineer's Inspection and RFI.
- Preparing Interim Progress Claim (IPC).
- Preparing the documents for Testing and Commissioning and performing Testing and Commissioning and making report.

COMPLETED CONSTRUCTION PROJECTS:

- KMG BRIDGE PROJECT: "Construction of KMG (Kanchpur, Meghna, Gomti) 2nd parallel Bridges and Rehabilitation of existing Bridges Project"- worked as local in-charge of SEC under OSJI (JFE ENGINEERING CORPORATION).
- JAPAN EAST WEAST MEDICAL COLLEGE HOSPITAL: Plan, Design & Supervise Installation works of Electrical System, Lighting System and HVAC System.

SENIOR ENGINEER, SALES & TECHNICAL SUPPORT AT MAMPOWER LIMITED/ SUPERIOR BUILDERS & ENGINEERS LTD. DURATION: APRIL 2017 – JUNE 2018

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Plan, Design of Electrical Sub-Station for Industrial, commercial and Residential Holdings,
- Electrical Distribution System with 33/11kV and 11kv/0.415kV Substation both outdoor and indoor electrical system as per requirements of BNBC, Alliance Bangladesh, Accord Bangladesh etc.
- Support Sales Team technically with Design and Drawings of Electrical System SLD/OLD.
- Preparing the Quotation and Offer for the Electrical System, Substation, Distribution Boards, Power Factor Correction/Improvement (PFI) Plant and BBT System.
- Preparing the technical Specification of Electrical switchgear and protection system (FDB, MDB, SDB, PFI PLANT) as per requirements of BNBC, Alliance Bangladesh, Accord Bangladesh etc.
- Busbar Trunking (BBT) System, drawing by 3D software (CAD Profi) and visiting Site for taking measurement of BBT System (Indoor BBT & Outdoor BBT)
- Meeting with Project Engineer & Consultant as Conrtactor/Supplier of Transformer, Substation, BBT,
 Distribution Boards (FDB, MDB, SDB) and Power Factor Correction/Improvement (PFI) Plant

ELECTRICAL ENGINEER >> ELEMENTS BANGLADESH DURATION: NOVEMBER 2014 – APRIL 2017

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Plan, Design & Draw Electrical System for Industrial, commercial and Residential Buildings.
- Draw Electrical Single Line Diagram (SLD) for Electrical system.
- Plan, Design and Supervision of Electrical Sub-Station for Industrial, commercial and Residential Holdings,
- Electrical Distribution System with 33/11kV and 11kv/0.415kV Substation both outdoor and indoor electrical system as per requirements of BNBC, Alliance Bangladesh, Accord Bangladesh etc.
- Plan, Design & Supervise Installation works of Lightning Protection System (LPS) for Structure.
- Plan, Design & Supervise Installation works of Lighting system design and drawing by DIALux Software as per requirements of USGBC, Green Buildings Rating System, LEED, Accord and Alliance of Bangladesh etc.
- Design Fire Detection systems according BNBC, ACCORD, ALLIANCE, and NFPA Standard. Lighting protection system as per BNBC, NFPA, Accord Bangladesh, and Alliance Bangladesh.
- Meeting with project Owner & Project Engineer & Contractor/Supplier of Transformer, Substation, BBT,
 Distribution Boards (FDB, MDB, and SDB) and Power Factor Correction/Improvement (PFI) Plant as Electrical Engineering Consultant.

COMPLETED KEY PROJECTS:

- KNIT ASIA LTD UNIT-2: Plan, Design & Supervise Installation works of Electrical System for the Industrial Complex with 33/11KV & 11/0.415KV Substations.
- **AKH ECO-APPARELS LTD**: Plan, Design & Supervise Installation works of Electrical System for the Industrial Complex with 33/11KV & 11/0.415KV Substations.
- **TEAMTEX ECO-APPARELS LTD:** Plan, Design & Supervise Installation works of Electrical System for the Industrial Complex with 11/0.415KV Substation.
- COLORS AND STITCHES LTD: Plan, Design & Supervise Installation works of Electrical System for the Industrial Complex with 11/0.415KV Substation.
- Worked as team member for Energy Audit & Preparation of Report for Analyzing Flue gas, Thermal Efficiency, Electrical Efficiency and Electrical Safety of Generator, Boiler, Stenter, Dryer and Compressor at more than 15 factories/plants in all over Bangladesh.

REFERENCES:

1. Md. Mafizur Rahman Ahsan

B.Sc. Engg. ME, BUET Sr. Design Engineer ELEMENTS BANGLADESH Mobile: +8801818345345

Email: ahsan1028@yahoo.com

2. Mohammed Shahadat Hossain

Electrical Engineer, Project Division Sanyo Engineering and Construction Inc.

Mobile: +88 01787130202

Email: shahadat@secbangla.com

DECLERATION:

I hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge.

Engr. Abdul Kadir Sarker